<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Journey Toward Peace</title>
    <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Journey Toward Peace</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Journey Toward Peace {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 18:56:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Paying for Therapeutic Boarding School/Residential Treatment for your Child</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/paying-for-therapeutic-boarding-school-residential-treatment-for-your-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 18:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/paying-for-therapeutic-boarding-school-residential-treatment-for-your-child/</guid>
      <description>If you have a child that is really struggling in school, at home, or making bad choices in social situations, and you are considering a therapeutic boarding school or residential treatment center, it can be overwhelming. The first thoughts are often, how will you possibly pay for it and how much will it cost. I work with parents every day that are faced with this challenge and I make the following suggestions so parents understand what options are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paying for Therapeutic Boarding School/Residential Treatment for your Child-(copy)</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/paying-for-therapeutic-boarding-school-residential-treatment-for-your-child-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 18:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/paying-for-therapeutic-boarding-school-residential-treatment-for-your-child-copy/</guid>
      <description>If you have a child that is really struggling in school, at home, or making bad choices in social situations, and you are considering a therapeutic boarding school or residential treatment center, it can be overwhelming. The first thoughts are often, how will you possibly pay for it and how much will it cost. I work with parents every day that are faced with this challenge and I make the following suggestions so parents understand what options are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting Programs-things I have learned</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/program-visits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/program-visits/</guid>
      <description>Since the beginning of 2019, I have been traveling a lot! I have made it a priority to visit as many programs as I possibly can, so that I can learn as much as possible about how things are changing and how treatments are evolving. I feel it is important for me to really get to know different programs&amp;ndash;the facility, the ammenities, the staff, even the food provided. Each has something that makes it different than the others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Descriptions for Teens with Emotional or Behavioral Disorders </title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/program-descriptions-for-teens-with-emotional-or-behavioral-disorders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 15:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/program-descriptions-for-teens-with-emotional-or-behavioral-disorders/</guid>
      <description>After visiting a wide range of therapeutic programs, families can rely on an IECA member to guide them through the critical process of finding the right program for their child. The level of placement recommendation is determined by a very thorough process that includes the independent educational consultant working with the family, records review, and speaking with professionals that are involved with the case. Listed below are program descriptors for the continuum of care that is available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adolescents and Porn Addiction</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/adolescents-and-porn-addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 18:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/adolescents-and-porn-addiction/</guid>
      <description>Studies indicate that for many, sexual problematic behavior first begins during the adolescent years. According to Youth First, the average age of a child the first time they see internet pornography is 11 years. Some studies indicate the actual age may be as young as 7 years. Early intervention is essential for avoiding a lifetime of future problems from untreated compulsive sexual behavior. Psychotherapy and the development of values-based characteristics are key aspects to treating these issues in teens and young children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with an IECA Member Educational Consultant</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/working-with-an-ieca-member-educational-consultant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/working-with-an-ieca-member-educational-consultant/</guid>
      <description>IECA member consultants who specialize in therapeutic placements have extensive experience with mental health diagnoses, adolescent behaviors, substance abuse, emotional disabilities, and learning differences. They are able to help families during a time of crisis and offer support and direction to recommend the best intervention and solution.
When your child, adolescent, or young adult is not succeeding in their current school, college, or home environment, IECA member educational consultants can assist with these common concerns:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional ABCs of Parents of a Struggling Adolescent/Teen</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/emotional-abcs-of-parents-of-a-struggling-adolescent-teen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/emotional-abcs-of-parents-of-a-struggling-adolescent-teen/</guid>
      <description>If you are a parent of a struggling child, you may be reeling with emotions. You are NOT alone! Many parents have been in the same position and find themselves seeking the assistance of an Educational Consultant.
Some of the emotions parents say they feel&amp;hellip;
Angry
Battered
Confused
Desparate
Embarrassed
Frustrated
Guilt Ridden
Hopeless
Isolated
Jittery
Kicked in the gut
Lost
Mad
Nervous
Overwhelmed
Powerless
Questioning options
Resentful
Scared
Traumatized</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy of Education Consulting</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/joy-of-education-consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/joy-of-education-consulting/</guid>
      <description>I have just placed a client in a wonderful residential treatment center, after working diligently to find just the right fit. I say it that way, because this was an exceptionally challenging case for several reasons. The timing was difficult, the age of the client was tricky, and several other factors came in to consideration during the process.
I enter in to each of my placements with one objective&amp;hellip;to do the very best I can to find the best treatment facility for the specific individual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can Journey Toward Peace help?</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/how-to-find-the-best-therapeutic-program-for-my-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/how-to-find-the-best-therapeutic-program-for-my-child/</guid>
      <description>If you are a parent considering a therapeutic program for your child, it can be overwhelming! There are so many programs available. It is difficult to get much information from a school&amp;rsquo;s website, because often programs have similar information posted. However, each program has its own personality and speciality, just as each child has a unique personality and talents.
Journey Toward Peace helps parents of struggling adolescents/teens find a program that is best for their specific needs and individual situations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Willing to do whatever it takes?</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/willing-to-do-whatever-it-takes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/willing-to-do-whatever-it-takes/</guid>
      <description>I was watching an episode of Dr. Phil the other day, and is often the case, the show was about an out of control teen and the resulting chaos within the family.
I have to be honest, I am sucked in to these particular stories, because of my own experience with an out of control teen. I have such empathy for the families and the teens. I must admit, I have a tendency to compare the situation I was in, with the stories I am watching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips for Visiting Therapeutic Programs</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/10-tips-for-visiting-therapeutic-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/10-tips-for-visiting-therapeutic-programs/</guid>
      <description>An onsite visit will help you evaluate whether a particular therapeutic program is a good fit for your child and your family. Below are 10 tips to consider when visiting:
 Learn about the program prior to your visit.
Check out the program&amp;rsquo;s website. If you are visiting multiple programs, make sure to have notes available to refresh your memory about each just before you arrive. Reserve time to spend at least a half day at each location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trauma and Healing</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/trauma-and-healing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/trauma-and-healing/</guid>
      <description>When speaking with mental health professionals, the discussion often involves trauma as a factor in mental health and addiction. The research from ACE (Adverse Childhood Experiences) Study, indicates that the long-lasting effects of childhood trauma is significant. The need to uncover the underlying trauma is critical in treating addiction and mental illness successfully. It is very important for clients to have a safe therapeutic environment, so they will be able to reveal their trauma history, and start the healing process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if?</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/what-if/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/what-if/</guid>
      <description>I recently received a call from by best friend. She lives in Virginia, where we met 19 years ago. We have lived in different states for 17 of the 19 years we have known each other. However, we have remained close. We share our fears for our children, our aging parents, extended family, etc. We also talk about mutual friends we have from when we lived in the same area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boundaries</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/boundaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/boundaries/</guid>
      <description>Setting boundaries with our children is one of the most important things we can do for them. It is our responsibility as parents. However, setting firm boundaries with our children, especially our teen children, is very difficult!
We have to follow some basic rules when setting boundaries for our children, as well as others:
 Know your limits and your expectations.  If you feel strongly about certain things such as academics, chores, peer relationships, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of a Therapeutic Boarding School</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/benefits-of-a-therapeutic-boarding-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/benefits-of-a-therapeutic-boarding-school/</guid>
      <description>Therapeutic boarding schools are residential facilities designed to house struggling teens or adolescents while they get intensive, ongoing help with a range of issues. The benefits of a therapeutic school are many, because the facilities provide everything a teen, and their family, need to support recovery.
It may seem drastic for parents to place their child in a boarding school, but often it is the best solution for the family. It is important for a family to compare therapeutic boarding school programs, because they offer different programs for therapy, academics, and family involvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helpful Websites:</title>
      <link>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 15:34:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journeytowardpeace.com/blog/2/</guid>
      <description>National Assoication of Therapeutic Schools &amp;amp; Programs- www.natsap.org
Substance Abuse &amp;amp; Mental Health Services- www.samhsa.gov
Independent Educational Consultant Association- www.iecaonline.com
Wrightslaw Special Education Law &amp;amp; Advocacy- www.wrightslaw.com
National Counceil for Behavioral Health- www.thenationalcouncil.org
Addiction Technology Transfer Center Network- www.attcnetwork.org</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>